<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>auburn on Academic</title>
    <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/tags/auburn/</link>
    <description>Recent content in auburn on Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Ryan McGill</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ryanamcgill.github.io/tags/auburn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HARA: Hybrid Analog-digital Retro-directive Antenna</title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/retrodirective/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/retrodirective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project&amp;rsquo;s primary objective is to create an IC capable of retro-
directive beamforming in a phased antena array system. This allows the
antenna to automatically point in the direction of the strongest signal
instead of spending time on beam steering techniques. Further, we can
create interesting configurations of the array for different applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am assisting a graduate student to test this design by measuring the
timing charecteristics of the system. Currently the IC design is being
optimized and fabricated with testing slated for Fall 2019. I have assisted
in charecterizing capacitor crystals for the IC using a FieldFox Spectrum
Analyze as well as designed a testing apparatus for the transmitter /
receiver. I was also able to begin soldering some of the components down
for one of the testing boards.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Radar Vulnerability Testing</title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/radar_vulnerability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/radar_vulnerability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t say too much about this project! Currently working for the defense
contractor Dynetics Inc. to investigate ways of &amp;lsquo;hacking&amp;rsquo; an army provided
phased array radar via hardware vulnerabilities. Current tasks include emulating the
radar hardware environment and investigating pathways to attack the system,
both from standoff distance and from an operational perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/radar/radar.png&#34; width = &#34;1000&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dynetics.com/&#34;&gt;Link to Dynetics Inc. &lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.eenewseurope.com/design-center/new-phased-array-radar-architectures&#34;&gt;Image source.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eMotes: Novel Disposable Airborne Probes</title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/emote/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/emote/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Association and GlobalSense partnered
to sponsor the eMote in order to take measurements from the atmosphere.
Data is streamed from an ensemble of sensors (up to 2080) to receivers
located on the ground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/emote/emote.png&#34; width = &#34;1000&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The system provides data on temperature, humidity, altitude, GPS, and
inertial measurements from the atmosphere. The receiver&amp;rsquo;s hardware consists
of the Tiva-C Launchpad and TI-MSP430. TI-RTOS (Texas Instruments Real-Time
Operating System) is used in order to wield excellent interrupt driven IO
from the antenna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/emote/system.png&#34; width = &#34;1000&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project has been ongoing since I have been an undergraduate at Auburn.
Currently I assist in testing the system, focussing primarily on the
receiver end of the project. We most recently concluded range and battery
testing. Future work consists of pulling wind vectors from the sensors as
well as measuring resonant frequencies of static structures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://file.scirp.org/pdf/WSN_2018072314435375.pdf&#34;&gt;Project overview and image sources.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
