<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors on Ryan McGill</title>
    <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/authors/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Authors on Ryan McGill</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Ryan McGill</copyright>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ryanamcgill.github.io/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello! I am currently searching for Ph.D. positions in Electrical Engineering starting in Fall 2020. Right now I am pursuing a B.E. in Computer Engineering at Auburn University where I work as an undergraduate research assistant for Dr. Mark Adams in the Sensors, Transducers, Optics, RF, and MEMS (STORM) Lab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While at Auburn, I have been able to assist on many projects ranging from quantum key distribution on a nano-satellite to radar vulnerability testing. For graduate school, I am interested in working with quantum electronics, specifically with optics and photonics. This area of technology is helping usher in next generation electronics, and I want to be a part of a program that is capable of bringing this change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past summer I was in Boston as a research intern at MIT Lincoln Laboratory. Here I analyzed the impact of large wind farms on air surveillance radar as a project from the Department of Defense. While there, me and a few other interns came up with a new architecture for American Sign Language translation which received laboratory funding to continue development at the university level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of research, I give tours to prospective engineering students as well as enjoy playing board games, ranging anywhere from &amp;ldquo;Dungeons and Dragons&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;UNO&amp;rdquo;. If you would like to challenge me in checkers or contact me for any reason, feel free to shoot me an email!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
