<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mitll on Academic</title>
    <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/tags/mitll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mitll on Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Ryan McGill</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ryanamcgill.github.io/tags/mitll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ENVOY: Enabling Natural-language Versatility and Opportunity</title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/envoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/envoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t say too much about this project! ENVOY is a system that will allow
natural-language communication between ASL and non-ASL users. This is done by
translating ASL to English, and then English back to ASL. Applications that
are in development today try to focus on translating ASL to spoken or written
English and stop there. This project is intended to &amp;lsquo;complete the circuit&amp;rsquo; by
translating the non-ASL user&amp;rsquo;s response into ASL. We are proposingthis idea
because ASL speakers prefer to communicate in, well, ASL!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is a part of the &amp;lsquo;Intern Innovative Idea Challenge&amp;rsquo; (I3C) that is
done during the summer at MIT Lincoln Laboratory. Currently the project has
passed the first round (staff voting) and is participating in the
second round (poster presentation).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind Turbine Impact on Air Surveillance Radar (ASR)</title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/windfarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/windfarm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t say too much about this project! Each year countries put up more and
more wind turbines that are only growing in size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Legacy radars are being impacted as wind turbine blades happen to have
similar radar cross sections as target aircraft. The spinning of these blades
gives a doppler return at the radar site. Further, wind farms generally
contain turbines that are spaced close together. All of these factors contribute
to pockets of low probability of detection and tracking which translates to
potential &amp;lsquo;holes&amp;rsquo; in air surveillance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
