<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mitll on Academic</title>
    <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/tags/mitll/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mitll on Academic</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Ryan McGill</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://ryanamcgill.github.io/tags/mitll/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ENVOY: Enabling Natural-language Versatility and Opportunity</title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/envoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/envoy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;MIT Lincoln Laboratory Intern Innovative Idea Challenge - Final Round - First Place&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;MIT Lincoln Laboratory Intern Innovative Idea Challenge - Round Two - Best Poster Award&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ENVOY is a system that will allow  natural-language communication between ASL
and non-ASL users. This is done by translating ASL to English, and then English
back to ASL. Applications that are in development today try to focus on
translating ASL to spoken or written English and stop there. This project is
intended to &amp;lsquo;complete the circuit&amp;rsquo; by translating the non-ASL user&amp;rsquo;s response
into ASL. We are proposing this idea because ASL speakers prefer to communicate
in, well, ASL!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two biggest challenges facing ASL translation are the lack of large datasets
to train systems and unreliable language models. In this project, we propose two
solutions that can help alleviate this problems and allow two-way communication
for deaf or hard-of-hearing individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/envoy/asl.png&#34; width = &#34;1000&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is a part of the &amp;lsquo;Intern Innovative Idea Challenge&amp;rsquo; (I3C) that is
done during the summer at MIT Lincoln Laboratory. Projects are proposed to
laboratory staff to decide which get funded and added to development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/envoy/team_photo.jpg&#34; width = &#34;1000&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyones hard work, we were able to secure funding to continue
creating this system for MIT Lincoln Laboratory!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/File:American_Sign_Language_ASL.svg&#34;&gt;Image source.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wind Turbine Impact on Air Surveillance Radar (ASR)</title>
      <link>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/windfarm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ryanamcgill.github.io/project/windfarm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Interference from wind turbines can degrade the performance of radar by providing
a large cross section and Doppler signal.  Further, wind farms generally contain
turbines that are spaced close together. All of these factors contribute to
pockets of poor radar performance near wind farms and is a concern for flight
safety.  As the investment in wind energy increases it is important to understand
the potential impact of these farms on legacy radar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src = &#34;/img/windfarm/size.png&#34; width = &#34;1000&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.windenergy.org.nz/improvements-in-technology&#34;&gt;Image source.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
